Finding Aid for the Eugene P. Nassar Correspondence Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Eugene P. Nassar Correspondence Collection
2007
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0644
.42 linear_feet
Biographical Note
Eugene Paul Nassar, a native of Utica, New York, is Professor Emeritus of English and founder of the Ethnic Heritage Studies Center at Utica College of Syracuse University. He graduated from Kenyon College in 1957, and then was a Rhodes Scholar ( Worcester College, Oxford University) taking an M.A. in 1960. In 1962 he received a Ph.D. in English and American Literature from Cornell University. He is the author of books on Wallace Stevens, Ezra Pound, Dante, and of two books of literary essays. Nassar’s collection of prose poems, Wind of the Land, was published in 1979. He has also written a number of articles for scholarly journals.
Scope and Content Note
This small collection .21 linear feet is made up of photocopies of correspondence between Eugene Nassar and Cleanth Brooks, and between Nassar and John Crowe Ransom, for the years 1966-1993. The collection also contains an obituary of Cleanth Brooks and two articles by Eugene Nassar “Rhodes Institutes in America?” in the American Oxonian and “Symbols and Texts: A Personal Sketch of Literary Criticism Since the Fifties” in The Virginia Quarterly Review, Vol. 67, Winter 1991, No. 1.
- Correspondence—Outgoing—Eugene P. Nassar to Cleanth Brooks, Feb. 13, 1978—Jan. 29, 1980 (Folder 1)
- Correspondence—Outgoing—Eugene P. Nassar to Cleanth Brooks, Aug. 24, 1985 –Jan. 4, 1988 (Folder 2)
- Correspondence—Incoming—Cleanth Brooks to Eugene Nassar, June 14, 1974–Jan. 26, 1978 (Folder 3)
- Correspondence—Incoming—Cleanth Brooks to Eugene Nassar, May 4, 1978–June 28, 1979 (Folder 4)
- Correspondence—Incoming—Cleanth Brooks to Eugene Nassar, Feb. 6, 1980 --Oct. 23, 1981 (Folder 5)
- Correspondence—Incoming—Cleanth Brooks to Eugene Nassar, Dec. 23, 1981–Feb. 22, 1988 (Folder 6)
- Correspondence—Incoming—Cleanth Brooks to Eugene Nassar, Dec. 8, 1988–May 14, 1993, and 3 undated (Folder 7)
- Correspondence—Incoming—John Crowe Ransom to Eugene Nassar, Jan. 25, 1966–Dec. 12, 1966 (Folder 8)
- Obituary—Cleanth Brooks, May 12, 1994 (Folder 9)
- “Rhodes Institutes in America?” by Eugene Paul Nassar in The American Oxonian (Folder 10)
- “Symbols and Texts: A Personal Sketch of Literary Criticism Since the Fifties” by Eugene Nassar in The Virginia Quarterly Review, Vol. 67, Winter 1991, No. 1 (Folder 11)